Lacey Family Papers, 1790-1903 Ms 3
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Lacey Family Papers, 1790-1903
Ms 3
Fairfield Museum and History Center
1.0 linear ft.
This collection contains papers relating to the Lacey family of Fairfield, CT including financial records and account books.
(3 boxes, 480 items, 10 oversize items)
Lacey family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Scope and Contents note
In one full box and two half-size boxes are included mill ledgers and account books, bills, correspondence, deeds, estate and probate papers, military and legal papers, maps, newspaper clippings, and promissory notes. There are ten oversize ledgers. Most folders are arranged alphabetically, ledgers by date.
Biographical/Historical note
The Lacey fulling mill, established around 1800, was destroyed by the approach of the Merritt Parkway in the 1930's. It was located at the corner of Congress Street and Easton Turnpike, Fairfield, CT.
Daniel Lacy was the son of John Lacy and Mary Hubbell, born about 1743 at Fairfield and died 17 December 1828 at Stratfield. He married Tabitha Hubbell, daughter of Jabez and Sarah Hubbell. She was baptized 17 March 1751 at Stratfield and died 9 August 1814 at Stratfield. They had 5 children, John, Daniel, Sarah, Michael and Squire.
Daniel and Tabitha Lacy's first son was John (Sept. 1776-25 June 1856) at Stratfield. He married Eunice Wilson (c.1784-17 February 1840), daughter of Robert Wilson II. They had Urban Lacy (1805-20 March 1877) who married Mary Ann Sherwood (c.1816-c.1879), daughter of Ephraim Sherwood and Robert (5 May 1810-23 November 1832). Urban and Mary Ann had Eugenia. Eugenia G. (1844-c.1909) married Joseph Hallock and moved to New York City.
Daniel Lacy, born c. 1778, moved to Lockport, NY and married Mary. The had one son, Henry E.
Sarah Lacy (June 1786-4 April 1857) married Ephraim Seeley Sherwood and was his second wife.
Michael Lacy (c.1784-12 November 1835) married Betsey Wilson (1785-14 December 1823), daughter of Robert and Eunice Morehouse Wilson. They had Daniel F. Lacy and Levi L. Wilson (1812-1 April 1845). Michael's second wife was Racilla Wilson (1799-21 July 1879). They had Michael B. Lacy (1 February 1832-17 August 1903). He married Ann Elizabeth Wilson (13 October 1840-11 January 1906). They had Charles C. Wilson.
Daniel and Tabitha's last child was Squire (1789-27 December 1819). He married Julia.
Custodial History note
These items were donated by Charles C. Lacey and Edward Cullen.
Lacey, Michael B.; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Mills and mill-work--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Promissory notes--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County--Maps.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Receipts (financial records); Textile finishing--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Textile industry--Connecticut--Fairfield.
- Academic memorabilia (1 genealogy note), Box I-Folder A; 20.0 items
- Bills and bills receipted, 1814-1877; Box I-Folder B; 21.0 items
  - Eli Adams
  - Atkinson and Billings
  - Wm. S. Atkinson
  - James Baldwin
  - Silliman Bibbins
  - Bishop and Cullinan
  - E. Blakeman
  - Israel W. Blakeman
  - Benjamin Brothwell
  - Moses Buckley
  - George Burr
  - Isaac M. Conklin
  - Carlos Curtis
  - Hubbell Curtis
  - Henry Gilbert
  - Sloop Guilford
  - Benjamin Hall
  - Levi Hall
  - Lorenzo Hall
  - Daniel Hopkins
  - James Hopkins
- Bills and bills receipted, 1815-1835; Box I-Folder C; 20.0 items
  - Charles Hubbell
  - George Hubbell
  - Mary Hubbell
  - Nehemiah Jennings
  - David Lacey
  - Mary Lacey
  - Ezra Morehouse
  - Wm. B. Nash
  - North School (Wm. L. Hall)
  - Z. Sanford
  - Rosewll Seeley
  - Ephraim L. Sherwood
  - Hubbell Thompson
  - Smith Thompson
  - S. G. Sterling
  - C. Tomlinson
  - Harry Warner
  - Daniel Wheeler
  - N. C. Wheeler
  - Nathaniel Wilson
- Bills and bills receipted, 1813-1819; Box I-Folder D; 28.0 items
  - Thomas C. Wordin
- Bills and bills receipted, 1820-1824; Box I-Folder E; 26.0 items
  - Thomas C. Wordin
- Bills and bills receipted, Michael Lacey's estate, 1826, 1836, n.d.; Box I-Folder F; 22.0 items
  - Eli Adams, 3.0 items
  - Joseph Brothwell
  - Roswell Brothwell
  - Carlo Curtis
  - E. Fanton, 2.0 items
  - Joshua Gibbs
  - Bradley Gould
  - Benjamin Hall
  - Abel Hubbell
  - Nathan Jennings
  - James Jones
  - L. L. Lacey
  - Peter C. Pixlee
  - Elijah Seeley
  - Alva Sherwood
  - Joseph Silliman
  - Smith Thompson, 2.0 items
  - Isaac Whitehead
- Bills and bills receipted; town and toll tax (Easton and Fairfield), 1834-1903; Box I-Folder G; 102.0 items
- Correspondence, Box I-Folder H; 2.0 items
  - From B. Merchant to Urban Lacey, 1825
  - From Henry Lacey to Robert Lacey, 1831
- Deeds, 1800-1886; Box I-Folder I; 23.0 items
  - From Ashbel Steel to John Lacey, 1800
  - From Ezra Seeley to John Lacey, 1803
  - From Daniel Glover to John Lacey, 1807
  - From Daniel Lacey to Squier Lacey, 1811
  - From John Lacey, et. al to Samuel O. Seeley, 1821
  - From Samuel O. Seeley to John Lacey, 1821
  - From Nathanial Ruggles to John Lacey, 1823
  - From Robert Wilson to John Lacey, 1825
  - From Daniel Lacey to John Lacey, 1828
  - From Ephraim Sherwood to John Lacey, 1830
  - From John Staples to Levi Lacey, 1836
  - From Levi and Urban Lacey to John Staples, 1836
  - From Levi Lacey to Mary Ann Lacey, 1837
  - From Levi L. Lacey to John Lacey, 1838
  - From Daniel Lacey to Urban and Mary Lacey, 1839
  - From Daniel Lacey to Levi Lacey, 1842
  - From Daniel Lacey to Levi Lacey, 1842
  - From Levi Lacey to Urban Lacey, 1845
  - From Benjamin Wheeler to John Lacey, 1850
  - From Benjamin Wheeler to Urban Lacey, 1850
  - From Theodore and Mary Sherwood to Mary Ann Lacey, 1868
  - From Eugenia Lacey to Mary Ann Lacey, 1886
- Estate and probate papers, 1826-1868; Box I-Folder J; 24.0 items
  - Betsey Lacey
  - Daniel Lacey, 3.0 items
  - Michael Lacey, 15.0 items
  - Ephraim Sherwood
  - Unidentified, 4.0 items
- Legal and military papers, 1807-1842; Box I-Folder K; 5.0 items
  - subpoena, Hubbell vs. Fairchild, 1807
  - Urban Lacey's military certificate, 1835
  - Roger M. Sherman's opinion, 1842
  - writ, Edward Hill vs. Daniel Lacey, 1842
  - legal opinion
- Maps, 1829, n.d.; Box I-Folder L; 9.0 items
  - Daniel Lacey's estate, 7.0 items
  - Squire Lacey's lot
  - unknown lot
- Newspaper clippings, Box I-Folder M; 51.0 items
- Miscellaneous items, Box I-Folder N
  - promissory notes, 1809, 1836, n.d.; 19.0 items
  - loose items, 18.0 items
  - note book
- Account books, 1790-1806; Box II; 8.0 folders
  - 1790-1806, Folder A; 2.0 items
  - small size 1804-1855 and n.d., Folder B; 12.0 items
  - 1802-1806, Folder C; 2.0 items
  - 1805-1812, Folder D; 2.0 items
  - 1807-1889, Folder E; 3.0 items
  - 1810-1813, Folder F; 3.0 items
  - 1813-1814, Folder G; 1.0 item
  - copy book of Urban Lacey, 1810; Folder H
- Account books, Box III; 7.0 folders
  - 1814-1815, Folder A; 2.0 items
  - 1815-1819, Folder B; 4.0 items
  - 1819-1825, Folder C; 4.0 items
  - account and scrapbook, 1808; Folder D
  - account book papers (loose); miscellaneous accounts, Folder E; 26.0 items
  - book and miscellaneous accounts, Folder F; 26.0 items
  - loose papers from Oversize Item II, Folder G; 17.0 items
- Oversize Item I
  - Account books, 1806-1824; 10.0 items
  - Account books, 1806-1807
  - Account books, 1816-1824
- Oversize Item II
  - Account book, 1814-1909